八 年 后
好
Yes.
你失败了
You failed.
我没有
I didn't.
枪在我手里
The gun is in my hand.
我以为我拿到了
I thought I had it.
抱歉 爸爸 下次我会成功的
Sorry, Father. I'll make it next time.
永远不要以为任何事都理所当然
Never take anything for granted.
否则上帝会从你身边夺走它
God will take it from you.
上帝坏吗?
Is God bad?
上帝是公平的
God is fair.
你差点就抓到我了 是不是 小子?
You almost got me, didn't you, boy?
我的白发是从你那里还是
Did I get my white hair from you
还是妈妈那里继承的?
or from Mom?
你妈妈那里
From your mother.
我无法相信我们没有她的任何照片
I can't believe we don't have any pictures of her.
所有东西都在大火中烧毁了
Everything was destroyed in the fire.
你知道的
You know that.
我只能救你
I could only save you.
她漂亮吗?
Was she beautiful?
她很聪明
She was smart.
就像你
Like you.
我继承了多少?
How many did I get?
全部
All of them.
那我今天要去镇上 对吗?
So I get to go to town today, right?
你没通过生存测试
You failed survival.
已经三个月没去过了
It's been three months.
另外 我给你剪个很酷的发型
Plus, I just gave you a killer haircut.
相信我
Trust me.
你要先通过所有的测试
You need to pass all your tests first.
好吧 除了寻常的
All right, apart from the usual,
我有个五株蕨类订单
I have an order of five ferns,
两棵榕树
two ficuses,
以及大柱花
and the Columnea grandiosa.
是金鱼花
Gloriosa.
金鱼花
我今天带菲妮克丝去吗?
Am I taking Phoenix today?
今天不行
Not today.
已经很久没去了
It's been a while.
我说了不行
I said, no.
你要么松开皮带
You either loosen up that leash,
要么她迟早咬断它
or sooner or later, she's gonna bite it off.
跟赫尔南德斯去吧
Go with Hernandez.
日落前回来
Back by sunset!
我会的
I will.
嘿 赫尔南德斯
Hey, Hernandez.
嘿 宝贝
Hey, gorgeous.
♪ 飞吧 小鸟 ♪
♪ Fly, bird ♪
♪ 越过浩瀚的大海 ♪
♪ All across the mighty sea ♪
♪ 唱吧 姑娘 ♪
♪ Sing, girl ♪
♪ 为我唱出你的心声 ♪
♪ Sing your little heart out For me ♪
很不错
That's beautiful.
你编的吗?
You made that up?
我想是我小时候妈妈给我唱过
I think my mom sang it to me when I was little.
我只记得第一部分
That first part's all I remember.
你想去看她吗?
You wanna pay her a visit?
- 但我父亲不想让我...  - 如果你不说 我也不说
- But my father doesn't want me...  - I won't tell if you don't.
♪ 飞吧 小鸟 ♪
♪ Fly, bird ♪
警方已经对托马斯·汉尼曼医生发出全州警报
Police have issued a statewide alert for Dr. Thomas Hanniman,
据信他在底特律地区运营一个
who's believed to be running an organ trafficking ring
- 器官贩卖团伙  - 谢谢
- in the Detroit area.  - Thank you.
该市最近发生的绑架事件数量惊人
The alarming number of abductions has recently risen in the city.
这个事件还在继续 随着更多信息披露
This is a developing story. We'll update you
我们将为你及时报道
as more information comes to light.
现在让我们来看看周末的预测
Now let's take a look at the weekend forecast.
大家早上好 我是气象学家杰瑞...
Good morning, everyone. I'm meteorologist Jerry...
各位 拉 帮帮我
Everyone, pull. Help me.
它卡住了
It's stuck.
嘿 想试试吗?
Hey, wanna try something?
好吧
Okay.
转吧
Do it.
快点 快点
Faster, faster.
我头晕了
I'm getting dizzy.
嘿 大家进来 吃晚饭了
Hey, guys. Come on in. Dinner.
但我不想进去
But I don't wanna go inside.
快点 伙伴们
Come on, guys!
“圣约庇护所”
看谁快
Race you.
嘿 等等
Hey, wait up!
- 你玩得开心吗?  - 嗯
- You having fun?  - Mm-hm.
好吧 我们走
All right, let's go.
我要尿尿
I need to pee.
好的 快点
Okay, well, be quick.
我不想惹你父亲生气
I don't wanna anger your father.
♪ 飞吧 小鸟 ♪
♪ Fly, bird ♪
♪ 飞过浩瀚的大海 ♪
♪ All across the mighty sea ♪
♪ 唱吧 姑娘 ♪
♪ Sing, girl ♪
♪ 为我唱出你的心声 ♪
♪ Sing your little heart out For me ♪
哇 你真漂亮
Wow, you're pretty.
你叫什么名字 美女?
What's your name, gorgeous?
我叫瑞南
Mine's Raylan.
无所谓
I don't care.
我得走了 我父亲在等我
I need to go. My father's waiting for me.
我打个响指
I snap my fingers
他就会咬掉你的蛋
and he'll bite your testicles off.
哇
Wow.
好吧
Okay.
很抱歉我吓到你了
Well, I'm sorry if I scared you.
谁说你吓到我了?
Who said you did?
回头见
I'll see you around.
来吧 影子
Come on, Shadow.
你没事吧?
You okay?
没事
Yes.
只是个怪人
Just a weirdo.
是啊
Yeah.
这附近怪人不少
No shortage of those around here.
跟着他们
Follow them.
谢谢 赫尔南德斯
Thanks, Hernandez.
我们今天玩得很开心
We had a lot of fun today.
如果你同意 我下周再带她去
I'll take her again next week if you're okay with it.
不
No.
今天就够了
Today was enough.
- 这不关我的事 但是...  - 你说得对
- It's none of my business, but...  - You're right.
不关你的事
It's not.
你是个坏人
You're a bad man.
一个做过可怕事情的人
A man who's done terrible things.
至少 我知道你是这么想的
At least, I know you think that.
就像有时我会想起自己一样
Just like sometimes I do about myself.
战争改变了我们所有人
War changes us all.
没有灵魂能因此回归纯真
No soul returns holy from it.
别让她来为这付出代价
Don't make her pay for that.
谢谢
Thanks.
拜托 你介意把车挪到路边吗?
You mind moving your vehicle off the road, please?
这是...
This is...
这是回镇上的唯一道路
This is the only road back to town.
你当过兵吗?
You served?
当过
Yeah.
我们也当过
We all did too.
- 在伊拉克?  - 对
- Iraq?  - Yeah.
不光彩地从一场不光彩的战争中退役
Dishonorably discharged from a dishonorable war.
我得说这让我们感到某种方式的光荣 你会吗?
I'd say that makes us honorable somehow. Wouldn't you?
不会
No.
现在能把你的车开走了吗?
Can you move your truck off the road now?
当然 宝贝
Sure, baby.
你想怎么都行
Whatever you want.
这是下个月的课
Lessons next month.
好的
Okay.
我想明年去上学
I wanna go to school next year.
- 这就是学校...  - 真正的学校
- This is school...  - A real school,
和其他像我一样的孩子在一起
with other kids like me.
在家学习更安全
Homeschool is safer.
我不想安全
I don't wanna be safe.
我想当个普通人 我想有朋友
I wanna be normal. I wanna have friends.
- 我想过一种...  - 够了
- I wanna live a...  - Enough!
够了
Enough.
我曾经失去过一个女儿
I already lost a daughter once.
我不会再失去你
I'm not losing you.
但我很孤独
But I'm lonely.
你并不知道孤独是什么
You have no idea what it is to be alone.
你有我
You have me.
有你还不够
You're not enough.
你的新家在等着你
“圣约庇护所
"Covenant Shelter.
你的新家在等你”
Your new home awaits you."
影子?
Shadow?
影子
Shadow.
噢 天哪
Oh, God.
去箱子 快
The box! Now!
走
Go!
去找那女孩
Go get the girl.
开门
Open the door.
Open up!
搞什么?
What the fuck?
噢
Oh!
等等 兄弟
Hang on, brother.
张开下巴
Open your jaw.
别动
Stay still.
呼吸 兄弟
Breathe, brother.
这家伙是海豹突击队的
The guy's a Navy SEAL.
该死的海豹 兄弟
Fucking dead SEAL, bro.
最好离开那里 孩子
Better get out of there, kid.
他和你在下面
He's down there with you!
该死的瞎子在下面
Blind fuck is down there!
通知瑞南
Call Raylan.
金属箱里快灌满水了
Metal box is almost full of water.
你想看到那孩子活着...
You prefer to see the kid alive...
你就进来
you come in here.
你以为我跟你开玩笑吗?
You think I'm fucking with you?
不
No.
有根带电的电线快要到水里了
There's a live wire about to reach the water.
出来 不然她就要被电死
Come out, or she's fried!
聪明的混蛋
Clever fuck.
不用枪 嗯?
No guns, huh?
没问题
No problem.
你很坚强
You're tough.
但你已经完了
But you're done.
搞什么?
What the fuck?
哟 兄弟
Yo, bro.
呼吸
Breathe.
快 呼吸
Come on, breathe.
呼吸
Breathe.
是那个瞎老头干的?
The old blind man did this?
嗯
Uh-huh.
走吧
Let's go.
我能走
I can walk.
我说了我能走
I said, I can walk.
怎么了?
What's happening?
掩护出口
Cover the exits.
搞什么?
What the fuck?
他们还在下面
They're still down here.
怎么了?
What's happening?
- 他们是谁?  - 我不知道
- Who are they?  - I don't know.
你不用害怕 小姑娘
You don't need to be afraid, little girl.
这只是一个很大的误会
This has all just been one big misunderstanding.
你需要害怕的不是我...
It's not me you need to be scared of...
而是站在你旁边那个人
but the man standing next to you.
现在 我不知道他是谁
Now, I don't know who he is.
但我知道他不是谁
But I know who he's not.
我该告诉她还是你?
Should I tell her or you?
干掉他 兄弟
Finish him, bro.
不
No!
- 爸爸 醒醒  - 你不是很了不起吗?
- Dad! Dad, wake up.  - Aren't you something?
放开我
Let me go!
来吧
Come on.
不 没事的
No, it's okay.
是的 好了
Yeah, there you go.
好了
There you go.
你真的不记得我了 是吗?
You really don't remember me, do you?
也许这会有帮助
Maybe this will help.
看到没?
See?
什么...?
What...?
几年前 我们家发生火灾
Years ago, there was a fire in our house.
警察归咎于我
Cops blamed me.
我在监狱里呆了八年
I spent eight years in prison,
不知道能不能再见到你
wondering if I'd ever see you again.
我甚至不知道你是死是活
I didn't even know if you were dead or alive.
这混蛋一定是...
This creep here must have...
发现了你 把你带走了
found you and kept you for himself.
接下来是当地新闻,
Up next in local news,
今早底特律西部的一个毒品实验室起火
a meth lab caught fire in west Detroit this morning.
警方逮捕了主要嫌疑犯
Police were able to arrest the primary suspect.
该男子被拘捕 可能会因过去几年里
The man was taken into custody and could face charges
犯下的大量罪行而面临指控
for a large number of crimes committed over the past several years.
你不知道这一刻我已经等多久了
You have no idea how much I've been waiting for this moment.
他伤害你了吗?
Did he hurt you?
但他确实把你从我身边偷走了
But he did steal you away from me,
现在他必须死 明白吗?
and now he must die, you understand?
杀了他
Kill him.
- 不  - 你他妈干什么?
- No.  - Fuck are you doing?
别在我孩子面前动手 去外面
Not in front of my kid. Do it outside.
醒醒 你个瞎蛋
Wake up, you blind fuck.
噢 妈的
Oh! Fuck!
该死的胆小鬼
Fucking coward.
把她带到车上去 我去抓这混蛋
Take her to the truck while I hunt this motherfucker.
走吧
Let's go.
- 让我走  - 你怎么回事?
- Let me go!  - What's wrong with you?
想他妈回家吗?
Fucking wanna go home?
我才不管你是谁
I don't care who you are.
我要教你些该死的礼貌 哟
I'm gonna teach you some fucking manners, yo.
你这不领情的小婊子
You ungrateful, little bitch.
不
No.
停手
Stop.
求你了
Please!
停手
Stop!
走 走
Move. Go, go.
快走
Move. Now.
走
Move!
抱歉 老兄
I'm sorry, man.
- 他回房子里了  - 我知道了
- He's back in the house.  - I know.
他想我们跟着他
He wants us to follow him.
这愚蠢的游戏够了
Enough of these silly games.
是他的夹克
It's his jacket.
好孩子
Attaboy.
等等
Wait.
停下
Stop.
那是真的吗?
Is it true?
继续走
Move.
我的真名是什么?
What's my real name?
快过来
Get over here now!
我的生日是什么时候?
When's my birthday?
- 我真正的生日?  - 别说了
- My real one?  - Stop it!
不 你闭嘴
No, you stop it!
走
Go!
嘿
Hey.
菲妮克丝
Phoenix!
冷静点 姑娘
Calm down, girl.
冷静
Calm down.
呆着
Stay.
把她放到车上
Put her in the truck.
喔 喔 喔
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
- 你的狗在那里  - 狗死了
- Your dog's in there.  - Dog's dead.
你不知道
You don't know that.
你想去看看吗?
You wanna go and find out?
不
No!
早上好 公主
Good morning, princess.
感觉如何?
How you feeling?
你没事吧?
You all right?
想和我坐在一起吗?
Wanna sit with me?
来 和我坐在一起 来吧
Come, sit with me. Come on.
好
Yeah.
就这样
There you go.
好了
Yeah.
门开着
Door's open.
你不再是囚犯了
Not a prisoner anymore.
你是说 我可以走?
You mean, I can go?
如果你愿意的话
If you want.
或者你也可以留在这里
Or you can stay here
弄清楚你到底是谁
and find out who you really are.
我有兄弟姐妹吗?
Do I have any brothers or sisters?
很不幸 没有
Unfortunately, no.
我的生日是什么时候?
When's my birthday?
二月二十号
February 20th.
我母亲叫什么名字?
What was my mother's name?
约瑟芬
Josephine.
我看起来像她吗?
Do I look like her?
像
Yeah.
你像她
You do.
塔拉
Tara.
那是你的真名
That's your real name.
塔拉
Tara.
那个人对你说的一切都是谎言
Everything that man told you is a lie.
他怎么了?
What happened to him?
他得到了他应得的
He got what he deserved.
嘿 我不抱歉
Hey. I'm not sorry.
你也不应该这样
You shouldn't be either.
我想走
I wanna go.
哪里? 你要去哪里?
Where? Where you gonna go?
我知道有个庇护所
There's a shelter I know.
就如我说的
Like I said,
你不再是囚犯了
you're not a prisoner anymore.
♪ 飞吧 小鸟 ♪
♪ Fly, bird ♪
♪ 穿过 ♪
♪ Out across the ♪
♪ 广阔的大海 ♪
♪ Great wide sea ♪
♪ 唱吧 姑娘 ♪
♪ Sing, girl ♪
♪ 唱吧 女孩 ♪
♪ 为我唱出你的心声 ♪
♪ Sing your little heart out For me ♪
♪ 飞吧 小鸟 ♪
♪ Fly, bird ♪
♪ 飞越巍峨的悬崖 ♪
♪ Fly across the mighty cliffs ♪
♪ 睡吧 姑娘 ♪
♪ Sleep, girl ♪
♪ 妈妈会给你一个晚安的吻 ♪
♪ Mama's gonna give you A good-night kiss ♪
妈妈?
Mom?
就像我说的...
Like I said...
他告诉你的一切都是谎言
everything he told you was a lie.
我的塔拉?
My Tara?
你...
You...
这么大了 呵
got so big, heh.
我能抱抱你吗?
Can I hug you?
过来
Come here.
噢 天哪
Oh, God.
Mmm. Oh, God.
噢 宝贝 我们太想你了
Oh, baby, we missed you so much.
嗯...
Mmm...
好了
There you are.
你真是个漂亮的孩子
You were such a beautiful baby.
咳出来
Get it out.
咳出来 来吧
Get it out. Come on.
好了 好了 好了
There you go. There you go. There you go.
- 抱歉  - 没什么可抱歉的
- Sorry.  - Nothing to apologize for.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
摧毁了我们家的那场大火...
The same fire that destroyed our family...
也损害了我的身体
it burned up my insides.
爸爸妈妈有过一个...
Mom and Dad used to have a...
厨房 嗯...
kitchen, heh...
在我们房子的地下室
in the basement of our house,
我们以前做饭的地方
where we used to cook.
那是为我们的生意
It was for our business.
你口渴吗?
Are you thirsty?
塔拉?
Tara?
我要死了
I'm dying.
什么?
What?
化学物质产生的烟雾...
The smoke from the chemicals...
让我的血液中毒并严重损害了我的心脏
poisoned my blood and badly damaged my heart.
我想我没多少时间了
I don't think I have much time left.
你还有什么可做的吗?
Is there anything you can do?
我听说你在我们的老房子里给我留了花
I heard you left flowers for me at our old house.
是真的吗?
Is that true?
噢
Oh.
你不希望
Weren't you wishing
妈妈健康的活下去吗?
your mama was healthy and alive?
希望
Yes.
我需要一颗新的心 宝贝
I need a new heart, baby.
但不是任意一颗心
But not just any heart.
医生说必须要是 呃...
Doctor said it has to be a, uh...
必须要是...
It must be a...
相配的供体
compatible donor.
比如一个直系亲属的
Like a direct relative.
你拿着能救你妈妈生命的礼物
You hold the gift that can save your mama's life.
宝贝 我需要这份礼物
And, baby, I need that gift.
我们最终会合二为一
We'll finally be together as one.
你会活在我心里
You'll live on in me.
回家吧
Go home.
走开
Go away.
我说 走吧
I said, go.
待着
Stay.
回家吧
Go home.
我希望你能理解
I hope you understand
这个过程的高风险
the high risks of this procedure.
我想我给你的钱足够了
I think I pay you enough.
闭上嘴做你的工作
Shut up and do your job.
她为什么还活着?
Why is she still alive?
如果她死了 她的心也会死
If she's dead, so is her heart.
没有合适的设备 我无法让心脏长时间保持活性
And I can't keep it fresh long enough without the proper equipment.
我必须在她还活着的时候把它摘除
I have to cut it out of her while she's still breathing.
嘿
Hey.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿 嘿
Hey, hey.
谢谢
Thank you.
你怎么了 伙计?
What's wrong with you, man?
他们在那里做的事是错的
What they're doing in there is wrong.
她是我们的“烹调师”
She's our cook.
如果她死了 就没有产品了
If she dies, there's no product.
如果没有产品 也就没有我们
If there's no product, there's no us.
明白吗?
¿Comprende?
还是他妈的错了
Still fucking wrong.
嘿
Hey.
- 准备好了吗?  - 好了
- You ready?  - Mm-hm.
走吧
Let's go.
搞什么?
What the fuck?
去看看吧
Go check it out.
嗯
Hm.
你杀了我兄弟
You killed my brother!
你这瞎眼怪
You blind freak!
我要把你的头像南瓜一样劈开 老兄
I'm gonna carve your fucking head open like a pumpkin, man.
这是为影子
This is for Shadow.
噢 妈的
Oh, fuck.
不
No!
是他
It's him.
他到底是怎么找到...?
How the hell did he find...?
该死的不忠畜生
Disloyal fucking animal.
一切正常吗?
Is everything okay?
是呀 一切正常
Yeah, everything's okay.
- 一切正常 我保证  - 宝贝 我该担心吗?
- Everything's okay, I promise.  - Baby, should I be worried?
不 不 一点都不用
No, no. Not at all.
我会照顾你 我照顾你
I got you. I got you.
没有电我就没法工作
I can't work without power.
呃...
Uh...
那就改变计划
Change of plans, then.
收拾你的东西 带上女孩
Pack your things. Bring the girl.
劳尔
Raul.
带人过来 杀了那个瞎子
Bring the men. Kill the blind man.
- 带多少人?  - 所有人
- How many of us?  - All of you!
走吧
Let's go.
他们会杀了她
They're gonna kill her.
这对我来说并不好
And that's not cool with me.
他们就要走了
They're leaving now.
你身后的梯子直接通向他们那里
The ladder behind you leads directly to them.
你最好快点
You'd better hurry.
往左走
Go left.
那边
That way.
他会杀了你们所有人
He'll kill you all.
去他的 我出去
Fuck it. I'm out.
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey! Hey!
早上好 混蛋
Good morning, motherfucker.
- 宝贝  - 嘘 嘘 没事
- Baby.  - Shh, shh. It's okay.
别出声
Stop it.
宝贝
Baby?
喂?
Hello?
我看不见你
I can't see you.
宝贝
Baby?
我在这里 你在哪?
I'm over here! Where are you?
宝贝
Baby?
我抓到你了 混蛋
I got you, motherfucker.
不
No.
不 不
No! No!
不
No.
菲妮克丝
Phoenix!
现在...
Now...
你会看到
you're gonna see
我所看到的
what I see.
菲妮克丝?
Phoenix?
停下
Stop.
噢 停下
Oh, stop!
你...
You...
你不要靠近我
You mustn't come near me.
他说的一切...
Everything he said...
都是真的
is true.
我不是你父亲
I am no father.
我杀人
I have killed.
我...
I...
强暴
have raped.
我...
I...
什么都不是
am nothing.
都不是...
Nothing...
就是个怪物
but a monster.
你...
And you...
不能在我身边了
cannot be around me.
永远
Ever.
所以 走吧
So go.
快 走吧
Now. Go.
走
Go!
噢 天哪
Oh, God.
塔拉?
Tara?
不
No.
不 不
No. No.
求你了
Please.
不 不 不
No, no, no.
我来帮你
Let me help you.
我可以救你
I can save you.
你已经救了我
You already have.
消防出口 保持区域畅通
嘿
Hey.
这儿还有空房间吗?
Think there's room for one more?
我肯定有
I'm sure there is.
你叫什么名字?
What's your name?
我叫菲妮克丝
My name is Phoenix.
屏 住 呼 吸 2
导  演
罗 多·赛 亚 格 斯
编  剧
费 德·阿 尔 瓦 雷 兹
罗 多·赛 亚 格 斯
主  演
史 蒂 芬·朗
布 兰 登·萨 克 斯 顿
主  演
马 德 琳·格 雷 斯